视频资料来自网络 版权归BBC所有
仅供学习交流使用 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
水平有限 难免有误 敬请谅解
翻译: jinmy99/natas/alice/Geoff
校对: riddle89/最沉重的负担
后期特效/压制: 最沉重的负担
今晚 我打了网球
Tonight, I play tennis.
理查德指着一辆面包车
Richard points at a minibus.
詹姆斯和两个男人握手
And James shakes hands with two men.
非常感谢 大家好 欢迎你们
Thank you so much. Hello!
Hello, everybody, and welcome.
非常感谢 谢谢
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Now...
好了 几年前
Now, a few years ago,
一家总部位于柴郡的 名叫BAC的工程公司
bosses at a Cheshire-based
engineering company called BAC
计划开发一辆车
decided they'd like to make a car.
既然他们在柴郡 我猜他们可能
Now, because they're from
Cheshire, I assumed it would be made
用缟玛瑙或者牛眼花纹玻璃来造车窗
from onyx and have bull's-eye glass
in the windows
后视镜也许就会弄成韦恩鲁尼耳朵的样子
但他们没有这么做
and then door mirrors made
out of Wayne Rooney's ears. But no.
他们认为这车
They decided it should have
应该使用福特货车的四缸发动机
the four-cylinder engine
from a Ford people van,
和F3赛车的变速箱
the gearbox from a Formula 3 racing
car
而车的内饰
and that it should be upholstered
也要用上不锈钢及防水材料
in the same stain-resistant and waterproof material
好比老人家里的拼装家具
that they use to line furniture
in old people's homes.
继而 他们把注意力放在了车的外观
And then they turned their attention
to how it should look.
市面上大多汽车设计的灵感来源
Most car designers,
for their inspiration,
来自像大猫 蝙蝠 战斗机
go to big cats
and bats and jet fighters.
但是这些柴郡的人们 一个都不喜欢
But the men from Cheshire decided
they didn't want any of that.
他们想要从这个玩意获取灵感
They decided to take
their inspiration from this.
比约克专辑里 冰岛机器人的设计
So, the styling of an Icelandic
robot from a Bjork pop video,
赛车变速箱 还有小货车的发动机
the gearbox from a racing car
and the engine from a van.
东拼西凑后的产物 就是它
Bring them all together,
and this is the result.
名叫Mono 它是个神奇的东西
It's called the Mono,
and it's amazing.
引擎来自福特多用途车
The engine may be
from a Ford people carrier,
但经由考斯沃斯调教 如今它输出280马力
but it's been fettled by Cosworth,
so now it produces 280 horsepower.
有了一台280马力的心脏
And fitting a 280 horsepower heart
对一台重量不过半吨的车
in a car which weighs
just half a tonne is...
最终结果 就没那么简单了
Well, the effects
are going to be profound.
我终于知道他们为什么
I can see why they lined it
使用防尿湿材料了
with material designed to resist
trouser accidents,
因为我的膀胱快炸了
because my bladder's gone!
完全兜不住了 我吓尿了
It's completely gone!
I've wet myself.
0到60英里加速 只需2.8秒
0 to 60 takes just 2.8 seconds.
理论极速每小时170英里
And in theory, the top speed is 170.
但是也许在实际中我们做不到
But in reality, it isn't,
因为它和Ariel原子有相同的问题
because the Mono has the same
problem as the Ariel Atom.
没有挡风玻璃
No windscreen.
70英里的时候 你的脸开始移位了
At 70 miles an hour,
your face starts to move about.
80英里每小时 肉就快吹掉了
And then when you get to 80,
it starts to come off.
90英里每小时 你要接受现实 去弄个头盔
'At 90, you're forced to accept
that really, you need a helmet.
戴上头盔 你要感谢
'With a lid on,
you can start to appreciate
这车是多么的聪明
'just how clever this car is.'
首先要说的 很舒适 没别的意思 真的是很舒服
First of all, I fit. I mean,
only just, but I do actually fit.
尽管它装配的是
And even though it has
类似于F1的推杆悬挂
Formula One-style
pushrod suspension,
驾乘感受却独树一帜 你可以称之为享受
the ride is sublime. You could
almost call it comfortable.
虽然 有人说 高转速时
Although, that said, at high revs,
整车会抖动并呜呜作响
everything starts to tingle
and vibrate.
但我不想详细解释 简单打个比方吧
I don't want to go into too many
details, but let me put it this way.
如果我是个女孩子 我会非常喜欢这车
If I were a girl,
I'd like it very much.
奇怪的是 纵使对眼子老太婆
Strangely, even cross-eyed women
都能开着它合法上路
can drive this car legally
on the road.
但它实际上是为赛道而生的
But realistically,
it's built for the track.
所以 我们就看看究竟如何
So, let's see what's what.
这和直线速度没什么关系
It's not really about
straight-line speed.
也不曾感觉有多快
It doesn't actually feel that fast.
当你习惯它时 其实也不觉得可怕
And when you get used to it,
it's not that scary, either.
诚实的说 我不像是在驾驶汽车
If I'm honest,
it's not really like driving, this.
更像是在指挥一支
It's like conducting an orchestra
训练有素的管弦乐队
of parts that know exactly
what they're doing.
他们都已经排练得很出色了
They're very well rehearsed.
那里圆号 这里小提琴
There goes the French horns,
and here are the violins.
刹车妙不可言 变速箱更是美轮美奂
The brakes, they're good.
Gearbox is fantastic.
它在不停地换挡 嗙 嗙 嗙
It really is an absolutely instant
change. Bang, bang, bang, ready.
不止这些
'And there's more.'
因为这些沉重的部件 发动机
Because all the heavy stuff,
the engine,
变速箱还有驾驶者 都在一条线上
the gearbox and the driver,
is all in a line,
低沉在车的正中间
low down in the middle of the car,
车的重心位置和蠕虫一样
it has the same centre of gravity
as a worm.
F1悬挂和定制轮胎 青梅竹马
Couple that to the F1 suspension
and the specially-made tyres,
过弯速度简直大到正无穷
and the cornering speeds
are simply immense.
为了展示如何的大
To demonstrate how immense,
我们在极速弯放置一个雷达测速装置
we've set up a radar trap
on the follow-through,
开标致208 以最快速度通过
and coming through it now, as fast
as possible, is a Peugeot 208.
每小时83.5英里
83.5 miles an hour.
接下来轮到宝马M3
'Then it was the turn of a BMW M3.'
喔 看一下 每小时90.25英里
Ooh, now, look at that.
90.25 miles an hour.
在尼桑GT-R小试身手后 我们放出了Mono
'After a Nissan GT-R had a go,
we unleashed the Mono.'
明白我的意思了吗
See my point?
它跑得很快 也很有驾驶乐趣
It is very fast, then, and it's fun.
但是可靠性怎么样呢
But what about reliability,
对于一辆小排量的英国小跑车
traditionally not a strong point
这在过去并不是重点
for small-volume British sports cars?
我第一次开Mono时 它自燃了
The first time I drove a Mono,
it set fire to itself.
第二次 引擎又坏了
The second time,
the engine went wonky,
第三次时 还没出厂就坏了
and the third time, it broke down
before it had even left the factory.
所以我想了想 这果然又是一辆典型的英国货
So I thought of it, really,
as another typically British,
搞砸了的好点子
badly-executed good idea.
虽然这么说
But since all those calamities,
但他们毕竟花了12个月设计制造并做细节处理
they've had 12 months to work
on the design and the detailing,
我不得不说 虽然它看上去不算成熟
and I have to say, it looks
not just very well thought out,
但绝对算得上制作精良
but absolutely beautifully made.
也不仅仅是细节让人惊叹
And it's not just the detailing
that's beautiful, either.
而是 当你向后站一步
When you stand back,
你会发现 这是我见过的 最让人激动的外形之一
that's one of the most exciting
shapes I've ever seen.
Mono是除了奶酪以外 柴郡最好的产品
The Mono is the nicest thing to come
out of Cheshire since the cheese.
但10万2千英镑的价格
But it does cost £102,000, and that,
对于一辆一年用两次的玩具来说 似乎多了点
for a twice-a-year toy, is a lot.
但从很多方面来讲 它有点像iPad
In many ways, then,
this is a bit like an iPad,
因为iPad也不便宜 你肯定也不一定需要
because that's not cheap either,
and you certainly don't need one.
但你就是想买一部
But you want one,
因为它实在令人爱不释手
because it's such a lovely...thing.
这车 这车真是极好的 我懂
It is. It's gorgeous. I know.
制作精良 如同珠宝一般
And beautifully made.
It's a piece of jewellery.
但是
But...
-什么 -10万2钱英镑
What? £102,000?
我知道 有点贵
I know, it is expensive,
尤其是当你知道
especially when you bear in mind
其它所有你能买的优秀的赛道日赛车 都要便宜很多
all the other brilliant track-day
cars you can buy for a lot less,
KTM Radical Ariel原子
the KTM, Radical, Ariel Atom.
-还有摩根3轮车 -不算 我说了优秀的
Morgan 3 Wheeler.
No, I said brilliant.
好吧 卡特汉姆R500
All right, the Caterham R500.
那是很棒的一款赛道日赛车 价格只有这辆的一半
That's a brilliant track-day car,
and that's half the price of this.
是的 而且那车很快的 这辆车会更快吗？
Yes, and that is enormously fast.
But will this be faster?
为了找到答案 我们要把车交给我们的圈养车手
To find out, we shall hand it over
to our tame racing driver.
有人说 他半夜闯入人们的家里
Some say that he breaks
into people's houses at night
并在厨房抽屉里 留下两把神秘的钥匙
and leaves two mysterious extra keys
in a kitchen drawer...
而由于他买了倍耐力牌的避孕套
And that as a result of buying
Pirelli condoms this week,
他现在已有17个孩子
he now has 17 children.
我们只知道 他叫Stig
All we know is,
he's called The Stig!
Stig蓄势待发 他出发了
Stig snaps to attention,
and he's off,
如跳蚤般弹射起步
flicking off the line like a flea,
尽管起始点是潮湿的
even though the start-finish line
was damp.
希望赛道的其他部分都是干的
Hopefully,
the rest of the track's dry.
飞快切入第一个弯 方向打得很急
Flying into the first corner,
he came in very hot there,
但可以摆平 完全没问题
but sorted it out.
No problem at all.
没有音响 当然了
No stereo, of course,
只有考斯沃斯调试过的引擎声
just the sound of that
Cosworth-tuned engine
他呼啸着过芝加哥弯 非常稳定 坚如磬石
as he zips round Chicago
absolutely rock-solid.
现在 锤头弯
Now, Hammerhead.
能不能展示出中置引擎的平衡性呢？
What will this reveal about
the mid-engine balance?
干净利落 牢牢抓住地面
No drama.That is properly nailed down.
看啊 一个优雅和谐的漂移
But look, a well-orchestrated drift
on the way out!
高转速带来的振动让Stig大湿一片
High revs now. The vibrations will
be stimulating his lady parts.
极速弯 对啊 他加了档位
Follow-through and yes, he actually
changed up through there.
Stig很勇敢 即使大难临头
Stig is brave,
even on the brink of a crisis.
精准的操控来到倒数第二弯
Controlling it beautifully
into the second-to-last corner.
呼啸着进入甘邦弯 赛级变速箱低声哀鸣
Screams up to Gambon,
racing gearbox whining.
侧滑出弯 冲线了
Slides it through,
and across the line.
好了 这里是卡特汉姆R500
Now...here we have
the Caterham R500,
圈速是1分17.9秒
which did it in 1.17.9, yeah?
BAC Mono...
1分14.3秒
1.14.3.
不是吧！
No way!
哇！我们这里第二快的车！
Wow! The second-fastest car
we've ever had!
真了不起
That is something else.
太棒了 好极了
Tremendous. Excellent.
现在 到了新闻时间
And now,
now it is time for the news,
好消息！
and it's good news,
达契亚“抹布”今年
because the Dacia Duster has been named
被提名为年度廉价四驱拖车
budget 4x4 tow car of the year.
-很好 好了 我买了一辆自行车 -我觉得你看上去变苗条了
Great. Now, I've bought a bicycle. I thought you were looking a bit trim.
好吧 你知道 不是我变瘦了
Well, do you know, it's not really
the weight that I've lost,
-而是我的核心 怎么说的？-核心肌群
but my core, what's it called?
Core strength.
我们这是《大话女人》节目还是什么？
Are we on Loose Women or something?
不 詹姆斯 你很清楚
No, James, as you well know,
我们在“最后的夏天档”多年了
we have for many years been
on Last of The Summer Gear.
自从我买了自行车后 让我快要疯掉的是
Since I bought my bicycle,
what's driving me mad
很多人来告诉我你要买一条弹力短裤
is the amount of people
who come and say
"You need to get lycra shorts now".
对啊 你要 因为那更舒服并且减少摩擦
Well, you do, because it's more
comfortable and it stops chafing.
不 哈蒙德 不需要
No, Hammond, you don't.
穿弹力裤的人们常说
People who wear lycra shorts go,
看啊 这又难又危险 我要特殊（保护） 你不要
"Look, it's difficult and dangerous,
and I need special..." You don't.
事实上 唯一我需要做出让步的是
In fact, the only thing I do wear
as a concession that I make
穿一件这样的T-恤
is this T-shirt, OK? This is
这是我独自骑车时穿的衣服的背面
the back of it as I'm riding along.
机动车驾驶员们 谢谢你们让我用你的路
"Motorists, thank you for letting me
use your roads."
LAUGHTER
因为我觉得这样才有礼貌
Because I think that's polite.
我不相信你竟然真的骑自行车 什么样的自行车？
I don't believe you have a bicycle.
What kind of bicycle is it?
不知道 就普通的
I don't know, they're all the same.
山地车？公路赛车？
Is it a mountain bike,
is it a racer?
当你去商店 你穿过门
When you went to the shop,
you walked through
走进自行车店 店员就会说：“天啊。”
the door of a bicycle shop
and the man went, "Oh, my God".
你说：“我想要。。。”
And you went "I'd like..."?
我只说了我能买一辆门口那款车吗？
I just said, "Can I have the one
nearest to the door?"
他本想说 你可以买一辆这款 1万英镑 或这辆
He was trying to say, "You can
have this one for £10,000, or this..."
我说 不 我只想要一辆自行车 500英镑
I said "No, I just want a bicycle."
500 quid.
他卖你的这辆车
This bicycle he sold you,
-是不是前轮比后轮要大很多的那种？-不是
is the front wheel a lot bigger
than the back wheel? No.
就是一辆普通的自行车 轮子一样大
It's just a bike. They're all the same.
后轮有没有两个小轮子？
Has it got two little ones
at the back?
没有 没有平衡辅助轮
No, it hasn't got stabilisers.
我不相信 我觉得这是一个新的谜团
I don't believe you, and I think
this has become a new mystery.
就像野人一样
It's like a yeti.
所以如果有人看见他
So if maybe somebody's seen him,
如果你看见杰里米在骑车 请写信给我们
if you have seen Jeremy
on his bicycle, write to us, please,
写“救命 我快笑死了” Top Gear 伍德兰 等等
at "Help, I've Burst From Laughing",
Top Gear, Wood Lane, wherever.
不敢相信
I don't believe you.
我要骑车。。。 不 我下周不能骑车来
I'm going to ride... No, I'm not
going to ride down here next week.
太2B了 我都不经常骑车去报刊亭的
That's idiotic.
I barely ride to the paper shop.
上周末谁看了F1英国站?
Now, who saw the British Grand Prix
last weekend?
观众：看了!
AUDIENCE: Yes!
你们可能已经发现比赛里有很多次爆胎
You may have noticed there were
a lot of blowouts, OK,
我必须得说我很同情倍耐力
and I must say,
I feel rather sorry for Pirelli.
最近几年
For the last few years,
他家的轮胎真的很好 抓地力好又耐用
their tyres have been really good
and grippy and lasted too long,
所以F1组织方跟倍耐力说
so the organisers said to Pirelli,
"你们能造一款比较垃圾的轮胎吗?"
"Can you design a tyre
that's a bit rubbish?"
他们就造了 于是现在所有人都在抱怨
So they did,
and now everyone's saying,
"你们造的轮胎真是垃圾"
"Your tyres are a bit rubbish".
怎样的垃圾轮胎才能称得上非常垃圾呢?
So how rubbish is too rubbish?
你觉得倍耐力研发这轮胎的时候花了多少经费
How much do you think Pirelli spent
developing those tyres?
这怎么也得…也要一百块吧?
It's got to be...100 quid?
这肯定得要上百万啊
It's going to be millions.
好 花了上百万英镑 开发一种轮胎
Yeah, millions of pounds
developing a tyre,
而市场反响是 人们到轮胎店换轮胎时
and all they get in response is
people going into tyre warehouses
会说 "我的车要换四条新轮胎 只要不是倍耐力的就行"
and saying "I need four new tyres
for my car, just not Pirellis".
对 我还在介绍STIG出场的时候说他们笑话
Right. And then I make silly jokes
when introducing the Stig about it.
他们真是事与愿违了
It's gone wrong! It backfired.
这就是我不理解F1的地方
This is exactly why
I don't get Formula One,
因为它本应就该在汽车科技的最前沿
because surely it should be the
pinnacle of automotive technology.
倍耐力应该竭尽全力地
Pirelli should make a tyre
造一款最好的轮胎
as good as it is possible
to make a tyre.
它应该有主动空气动力的设计
They should have
active aerodynamics,
它应该拥有世上最尖端的牵引力控制系统
they should have traction control,
the most sophisticated in the world,
防抱死系统 隐身斗篷 这类东西
ABS, invisibility cloaks, all that.
应该允许他们在轮胎上用任何他们想用的技术
They should be allowed to have
anything they want.
但问题是 比赛组织方想把F1变成
The problem is, the organisers
are trying to make Formula One
更能凸显车手能力的公平比赛平台 往往事与愿违
a level playing field to make it a
drivers' championship. And it isn't.
你把维特尔放到Marussia车队里
You could put Sebastian Vettel
in a Marussia
他也只能垫底 -正是这样
and he's going to come last.
Exactly.
我们应该把F1变成车厂间的较量
Let's just make it
a championship for car-makers,
任凭设计师们天马行空
and then let the designers
have completely free rein.
你知道我会怎么做
You know what I'd do?
我会做一辆跟赛道一样宽的赛车
I'd make a car that was the exact
width of the track.
LAUGHTER
这得多有才啊? -这有意思
How clever's that?
That's interesting.
但这只有在你排位赛成绩靠前时才用得上啊
That would only work
if you qualified at the front.
不 不必这样
No, you wouldn't have to,
因为这车会和TOP FUEL赛车一样
(Top Fuel 北美NHRA赛规下专用做直线竞速的赛车 燃料为硝基甲烷与甲醇混合物 0.7秒即可达到100英里时速)
because it would be a Top Fuel-type
dragster, OK?
弯道时候会非常糟糕
So it'd be very poor
around the corners
所以排位赛肯定垫底
and I'd qualify last,
但起步时候我可以在到达第一个弯道之前
but I would accelerate really
quickly past them all
超过所有的对手 然后让它展开
before the first corner,
and then it would expand.
啊它自己会展开啊
-我这样就能赢了啊
Oh, it grows.
I've just won the championship.
Jeremy 你说的这是Wacky Races
(Wacky Races 美国卡通频道赛车主题动画片)
Jeremy, what you're proposing
is Wacky Races.
我知道! 想象一下 你可以
I know! Just think,
you could have, like,
让狗狗当你的副驾 它在你边上
(模仿Muttley Laugh 该动画片中狗狗角色)
a dog as your co-driver that goes...
IMITATES MUTTLEY LAUGH
我要我的车前面有个巨型圆锯
I want a giant circular saw
on the front of my car.
但这是机智的设定 我每圈只能用它一次
But here's the clever thing.
I can only use it once a lap.
所以你有DRS区域 圆锯区域 这真是个好主意
(DRS区域 F1中允许使用可变尾翼的赛道区域）
So you've got DRS zone,
then the saw zone. It's a good idea.
我要把我的F1赛车装上时间穿越装置 你想啊
I'd fit my Formula One car
with time travel. Think about it.
比赛解说说道 "比赛开始了!James已经赢了"
The commentator would go "And
they're off! And James had won."
真机智! -我们解决了F1的问题
That's clever.
We've solved Formula One.
再次证明了 这个世界没我们不行啊
Again, the world just doesn't work
without us in it. No.
沃尔沃的新闻! -好耶
-他们发布了一款能自己停车的车
Volvo News! Hooray. They have
launched a car which parks itself.
而且是在你不在车里的情况下
And I don't mean you sit in it.
沃尔沃的主意是 你在办公楼门口停车 下车
The idea is, you pull up
outside your office, get out,
进你的办公室
go into your office.
车子自己会开走 找个停车位 我不是瞎编的
然后它自己停车入库
It goes off, finds a space, I'm not
making this up, and parks in it.
唯一的问题是 当你从办公室里出来
The only problem is,
when you come out of your office,
你怎么知道它停哪了啊?
how do you know where it's parked?
要是它停在了三条街远的地方呢?
But what if it had to park
three streets away?
或者它放弃找停车位直接回家了呢?
Or what if it's just given up
and gone home?
等等 它怎么知道停车位的规则
Hang on,
how does it know what the rules are?
那些停车位标志还有单黄线
You know those signs that go
with single yellow lines
还有那些在马路边划了两条线的车位
and those ones where there
are two lines on the kerb?
这相当复杂 而且这是瑞典的 瑞典人本来就搞不懂这一套
They're complicated. And it's
Swedish anyway, so it can't read it.
我最大的担心是
What worries me about this is,
路上以后会开满了没有司机的 有点犹犹豫豫的沃尔沃
the roads will be full of driverless,
slightly panicky Volvos
匆匆忙忙地开来开去
scurrying about going,
"我能停这吗?我能停那吗?我能去哪停啊?"
"Can I park here? Can I park there?
Where can I go?"
这会相当恐怖啊 -路灯杆才是问题
-为啥
It's going to be terrifying.
It's the lampposts. What?
所有的路灯杆上都会贴着"寻沃启示"
All the lampposts will have missing
Volvo pictures on. Aww.
"他只有一岁大 他的名字叫小蹄蹄
"He's only a year old
and he's called Tiddles
"他出去找停车位然后我就找不到他了"
"and he went off to find a parking
space and I haven't seen him since!"
不管怎样 我们继续
Anyway, let's move on.
最近接连发布了很多辆超跑
There has been a whole rash of new
supercars launched recently.
这是我感兴趣的一辆 法拉利
This is the one I'm interested in,
this Ferrari. Ooh.
确实很赞 V12发动机 800匹马力
Indeed, ooh.
It has an 800 horsepower V12.
而且它还有一套跟F1赛车上类似的KERS系统
It has a KERS system
like a Formula One car.
售价大约在一百万英镑左右
It's going to cost around a
million quid,
但我觉得它的名字起得有点问题
but I think they've got a bit
of a problem with the name,
法拉利管它叫"LaFerrari"
because they've called it
LaFerrari.
不好意思 这有何不妥 是叫这个名字啊
Sorry, what's wrong with that?
I mean, it is.
不 这是它的型号名
No, but that's the model name.
LaFerrari在意大利文的意思就是"法拉利"
所以这辆车就是法拉利-法拉利
(意大利文的La类似英语的the)
LaFerrari means "the Ferrari",
so that's the Ferrari the Ferrari.
啊对 我特别想要的超跑是帕加尼
Oh, yeah. The supercar
I really want is by Pagani.
他们有辆新车出来了 但又不完全是新车
They've got a new car out,
except they sort of haven't,
因为这是Zonda的另一个版本
because it's yet another version
老车型了 就是它
of the Zonda, their old car.
There it is.
-有什么新变化?
-除了价格 还真没啥变化
And what's new about that? Not
a lot, really, apart from the price.
这车售价是230万英镑
-什么! 这二手车要这么贵?
It's now £2.3 million. What?
Yeah. For a second-hand car?
没错
Yeah.
你们知道吗 我最心仪的一款车
You know, the one
I'm most interested in,
是迈凯轮P1 因为它售价一百万英镑不到
this is the McLaren P1, because this
is just shy of a million quid,
所以简直是特价 而且它有903匹马力 903匹!
so it's almost a bargain. And it's
got a 903 horsepower engine. 903.
让我觉得最不可思议的是
What fascinates me is,
它后面可以有个可升降的尾翼
there's a wing that comes out
of the back of it
尾翼上带DRS系统
which has got DRS on it.
众所周知 DRS系统 F1里用的 可变下压力系统
You know what DRS is, with the...
In Formula One, it opens.
如果你有903匹马力 你什么时候会想到
If you've got 903 horsepower,
when would you ever think,
"好 我要更快的直线速度
"Right, I need more straight-line
speed.
"我要开启DRS系统"?
"I'll deploy the DRS wing"?
好吧 这还是可能会发生的
Well, it could happen.
"那辆快递货车开得真快 看来我得开启DRS了"
"That post office van is getting
a shift on. I'll deploy DRS."
不不不不 你需要这个 你的DRS
No, you will need that, your DRS,
特别当你碰到在法拉利-法拉利里的我的时候
when you come across me
in the Ferrari the Ferrari,
因为 我刚刚没有说清楚
because, I hadn't read this
properly,
它确实有800匹马力 但是
it has got 800 horsepower
in the engine, but of course,
他有KERS系统
it's got a KERS system.
当你启用KERS系统用电机一起发力时
When you deploy it
and use the electric bit as well,
嗯哼 就变成963匹了
ahem, 963 horsepower.
而且所有这些动力都只传递到后轮?
-是的 没错
And is that all going through
the rear wheels? Yes, it is.
等下 这马力数据
Hang on, that's broadly
the same amount of power
和布加迪威龙已经不相上下了
you get from a Bugatti,
但威龙车身要比法拉利-法拉利重了一倍
which is almost exactly
twice as heavy
而且还有四驱系统
as the Ferrari the Ferrari,
and it has four-wheel-drive.
这货 才叫神作
-没错
That's going to be "an handful".
Yes.
让人激动啊 我真想去体验一下
-我很想开开这迈凯轮
Exciting, though. I want a go in it.
I really want to go in the McLaren.
这会是个很壮观的测试
That would be an epic test.
你开着那辆法拉利 你迈凯轮 我开着Zonda
You in that Ferrari, you in
the McLaren, me in that Zonda.
有人愿意看这个吗?
Anybody want to see that?
观众: 愿意!
AUDIENCE: Yeah!
我也想 我们努力一下看看这事能不能成真
So do I. Let's see
if we can put that together.
但你也知道 人们通常找到我们 然后说
But you know how people often come
up to us and say,
"Top Gear什么时候才会完结"
"When will Top Gear end?"
我们开着这些车起步后大概三分钟
About three minutes after us three
have set off.
恩 在一个大火球里结束
Yeah, in a big fireball.
有人愿意看这个吗?
Does anybody want to see THAT?
观众: 愿意!
AUDIENCE: Yes!
好吧 我们继续 我们这个节目已经播了11年了
Right, let's move on, because it is
now 11 years we've been on air,
但我们惊奇的发现
and in all that time,
从一开始 我们就从没测评过这一辆车
there is one vehicle that we have
never reviewed, which is a surprise,
它是最受欢迎的车
because it's the most popular,
最重要的车 也是世界上使用最频繁的车
important and used vehicle
in the world.
我说的 当然是出租车
I'm talking, of course,
about the taxi,
不管你到哪 出租车可谓人类运转的源泉
the lifeblood of people movement
wherever you go in the world.
英国对此的贡献无需多言
And Britain's contribution to
this effort needs no introduction.
它是任何伦敦街景中的标志
It's a staple
of any London street scene.
现在大约有1万9千辆黑色出租车
There are currently
around 19,000 black cabs
在伦敦街头接送着人们
moving people across the capital,
这一大群的出租车每年行驶大约5亿英里的路程
and this vast fleet covers
almost half a billion miles a year.
那边还有一辆 他们真的是无处不在
There's another.
They are literally everywhere.
因为伦敦特殊的生活节奏
London life has caused the black cab
黑色出租车进化成了让人惊叹的高效运载工具
to evolve into
an amazingly efficient vehicle.
比方说 它著名的极小的转弯半径
Its famous tiny turning circle,
for example,
就是专为萨沃伊酒店门口的小环岛而设计的
(Savoy 伦敦最著名豪华酒店之一)
is the result of the need to tackle
the roundabout outside the Savoy.
还有就是出租车司机
Then there's the black cab driver.
世上没有其他的出租车司机需要像他们一样
No cabbie in the world
has to go through
通过名为"知识"的恐怖试炼
an ordeal as fearsome
as The Knowledge,
所有的伦敦出租车司机都要认得2万5千条路
which requires that all London
taxi drivers memorise 25,000 streets.
这个测试非常严格 事实上
The test is so tough, in fact,
所有的伦敦出租车司机都进化出了非常肥大的海马回突
that cabbies develop an extra large
hippocampus,
这是大脑中负责记忆 导航
which is the area of the brain
associated with memory, navigation
和对移民观点的部分
and views on immigration.
人车结合
Put this combination of man
and machine together,
结果那当然是毋庸置疑
and what you have is indisputable.
毫无疑问 无比明显 无可非议的
What you have is, without doubt,
obviously, unquestionably,
世上最好的出租车
no arguments,
the best taxi in the world.
真是这样吗？
Or is it?
纽约的出租车司机
The thing is, a New York taxi driver
对此说法很可能会不同意吧
would probably disagree
with that statement.
他会说"是啊 你们车的后排空间确实更大
He'd say "Yeah, you may have
more space in the back,
"但是你们伦敦出租车又慢又不舒服
"but your London taxi is slow
and the ride is terrible,
"我的黄色出租车有个大大的V8发动机 还有更好的悬挂"
"whereas my yellow taxi has
a big V8 and proper suspension."
但德里的出租车司机会说
But then a cabbie in Delhi would
say,
"我的印度出租车更经久耐用"
"My Indian taxi is built
to last longer".
总体上来说 世界上任何地方的出租车司机
Basically, every cabbie
everywhere in the world
都会抓住一个理由 说自己的出租车是世上最棒的
could argue for one reason or another
that their taxi is the best.
也就是说 如果他们真想知道
Which means, if we really want
to find out
哪个是世界上最棒的出租车
which is the greatest taxi
in the world,
只有一个方法才能评判
there is only one way to do it,
这就一如往常 要做到真金不怕火炼
and that is, as ever,
in the prism of the furnace
只有通过赛车的历练
through the looking glass
of the crucible of motorsport.
这就是我们全球大决战的地点
That means a race, and the venue
for our global showdown
是肯特郡的林登山
will be Lydden Hill in Kent,
在世界赛车界以唯一拥有自己的出租车办公室
famous throughout the motorsport
world
而久负盛名
for being the only race track
with its own cab office.
这个胶板搭的出租车办公室看上去离赛道也太近了点
That plywood cab office looks
perilously close to the track.
我真心希望它不会受到啥伤害
I sincerely hope no harm befalls it.
不管怎样
来看看我们这次出租车全球大决战的参赛车辆吧
Anyway, let's now meet our grid
of taxis from around the world.
代表大不列颠帝国 我们有1997年的Fairway
Representing Great Britain,
we have a 1997 Fairway driver which,
里程表上只有32万英里 新得像还没出磨合期一样
with a mere 320,000 miles
on the clock, is barely run in.
代表墨西哥 1970年大众甲壳虫
From Mexico,
a 1970 Volkswagen Beetle.
单单在墨西哥城 就有5万辆这样的车在努力营生
50,000 of these things ply
their trade in Mexico City alone.
代表美国 出租车世界中的泰坦
From America,
one of the titans of the taxi world,
纽约黄色出租车
a New York yellow cab.
福特皇冠维多利亚 后轮驱动
This particular one is a Ford Crown
Victoria, rear-wheel drive,
4.6升V8 想当年 开到130英里时速完全没问题
4.6 litre V8
and in its day, good for 130.
这是我们需要担心的对手
That's one to worry about.
代表印度 印度斯坦牌大使 在我们这可算是老家伙了
From India, the Hindustan Ambassador,
very much the old-timer here.
大使曾是印度最受欢迎的出租车
The Ambassador has been
India's favourite taxi
达55年之久
for an incredible 55 years.
接下来 来自南非 我们有这辆丰田海狮
Next, from South Africa,
we have this. A Toyota HiAce.
在大多数别的国家里
Whereas in most countries,
这是出租车的应急救援车
they will be rooting
for their local taxi,
你就知道南非人对此不屑一顾了
you can expect the South Africans
to be booing,
这些车因为他们野性狂暴 被人又恨又怕
because these things are hated and
feared for their wild aggression.
接下来是这个 代表德国 奔驰E系
Moving on to this, from Germany.
It's the Mercedes E-Class.
干净 智能 保养得天衣无缝
Neat, smart
and fastidiously maintained.
最后 代表俄罗斯 加长林肯
And finally, from Russia,
a Stretched Lincoln Town Car.
恩 它看上去不太像是辆出租车 可它真的是
Now, that might not look like a cab,
but it is.
在俄罗斯 有钱的大佬们用这种加长车做出租车跑来跑去
In Russia, rich oligarchs hail limos
just like this to get around.
所以 当你以为我们叫来一辆强劲有力 后轮驱动的
So if you think we've included
a powerful rear-wheel drive
长超9米的车只是为了来添乱的话
30-foot long car just in the hope
that it will cause chaos,
你可千万别这样想了
get that thought out of your head.
所以 这就是了 世上最具代表性的出租车们
So there we are, then -
the world's most iconic taxis,
泰然自若 准备为自己的国家争光添彩
each poised and ready to defend
the honour of its country.
好 出租车司机们
Now, the cab drivers.
自然的 因为我们这的比赛是如此重要
And naturally, because of the
magnitude of what's at stake here,
每个国家都派出了国内最顶尖的出租车司机
each country has sent its very best.
但他们肯定都会迷路或者别的啥了 所以 为了代替他们
But they all must have got lost
or something, so instead,
我们有这一帮不上台面的赛车手
we have the usual ragtag bunch
of racing drivers.
代表俄罗斯 房车比赛传奇 Anthony Reid
For Russia,
touring car legend Anthony Reid.
代表南非 房车比赛传奇 Matt Jackson
For South Africa,
touring car legend Matt Jackson.
代表德国 房车比赛传奇 Matt Neal
For Germany,
touring car legend Matt Neal.
代表印度 房车比赛传奇 Gordon Shedden
For India,
touring car legend Gordon Shedden.
代表墨西哥 房车比赛传奇 Paul O'Neill
For Mexico,
touring car legend Paul O'Neill.
代表美国 房车比赛传奇 Tom Chilton
For America, touring car legend
Tom Chilton.
然后就是在黑色出租车里的 我!
And in the black cab, me.
我们准备就绪 再次向基于赛车运动的科学研究的深渊中
So here we are, ready to plunge
once more into the abyss
勇猛前行
of motorsport-based
scientific research.
我想要指出 在仪表盘上供着自己信仰的神
I should point out that it's
the custom for Indian taxi drivers
是印度出租车司机的传统习惯
to carry a figurine of their chosen
God on the dashboard of their car.
我觉得我们的人做得稍微有点过了
I think our guy may have
overdone it a bit.
ENGINES REV, HORNS BEEP
这群家伙们有点不耐心了 不错不错
倒数5秒
The guys are getting impatient.
That's good. Five-second board.
出发咯!
Yeah!
南非飞驰而过
The South African is through.
纽约出租车在边上 德国 所有人都超过我了
New York taxi alongside,
German...everybody is through.
所有人 都超过我了
Absolutely everybody has passed me.
但这是马拉松 不是短跑
But this is a marathon,
not a sprint.
同往常一样 我严格规定了
'As ever, I'd issued strict
instructions
车与车之间严禁身体接触
'for the drivers to avoid
body contact.
很明显 南非选手没看到这一条通知
'Clearly, the South African
hadn't got the memo.'
南非选手完完全全疯了 根本失去了控制
The South African is completely
insane, largely out of control.
加长车的大漂移! 这可真牛逼
Huge slide from the limo!
That's incredible.
当俄罗斯加长车在弯道上奋斗的时候
'But while the Russian limo may have
been struggling in the corners,
我遇到了不少麻烦
'I had issues everywhere.'
恩 我爬坡时候被狠狠的甩下了
Yeah. I'm quite badly outpaced
on the hill,
直道时也是 转弯时也是
on the straights and in the turns.
这是我全部动力了
This is all I've got.
但是 我有个计划
'However, I had a plan.'
要说诡计多端 记住 伦敦出租车司机可是有"知识"的
When it comes to cunning, remember,
black cab drivers do The Knowledge.
我知道哪里能超近道 我悄悄地在这一拐
I know where all the shortcuts are.
I'll nip down here, love.
多亏我有超级小的转弯半径 我能搞定这个弯
Thanks to my super tight turning
circle, I can make this.
我又回到比赛中来了
That's me back in the race.
我敢说不只是回到比赛中
而且我还领先了
I'd say more than back in,
I am leading it.
只可惜我的出租车司机同行们对我这个策略不怎么欣赏
'Sadly, my fellow cabbies weren't
impressed by this tactic
所以当他们追上我时
'and when they caught up with me,
他们立刻就显示出了他们的不满
'they were quick to show
their displeasure.'
他就直接撞上来了 这真是 开玩笑吧
He's just ramming me! That is just...oh, you're joking.
来自其他国家的友善推搡
Yeah. Some good-natured jostling from the other nations.
赛程进行过半 局势尚不明朗
'With the race now at the halfway point, no clear leader was emerging,
也就意味着 车手们开始煽风点火了
'which meant inevitably that the drivers began to turn up the heat.'
那里撞了一下 不过我们没事
There's been a crash, but we're OK.
受够了南非的恶棍做派
'Fed up of the South African's hooliganism,
豪华轿车给了他一记自食苦果
'the limo gave him a taste of his own medicine.'
哦 哇 又被推挤了下
Oh! Whoa! Getting a push now.
这可是我的极速了
This is by far the fastest I have been.
老天 抱歉 哦 那是墨西哥车 是吧
Oh, Jesus. Sorry about that. Oh, God, it's the Mexican, isn't it?
后果严重
It's going to be bad.
还有两圈结束 大家仍然在冲刺 但这时
'With just two laps to go, everybody was still running. But then...'
豪华车自己出去了
Oh, the limo takes himself off entirely.
老天 俄罗斯车出局了
Oh, my word! That is Russia taken out.
事实上 美国车也自己出去了
In fact, America has taken itself out as well.
所以 在场上的 有甲壳虫
Right, still in play, we have the Beetle...
奔驰车表现不错
The Mercedes is holding up well.
很稳定 几乎没怎么受伤
It's really sustained very little damage.
但横行霸道的南非车似乎另有打算
'But the marauding South African had other ideas.'
哦 运气真差
Oh! Bad luck.
到了最后一圈
'Now into the final lap,
为了打败其他选手 我暗中走了另一条道
'and desperate to beat the remaining runners, I took another sneaky turn.'
哈哈
Ha-ha!
终点线在那儿
There is the finish line.
我觉得我赢定了
I think I can win this.
我觉得我能赢 哦 不 不
I think I can win... Oh, no, no!
我有点落后了
It's entirely possible that I am a bit last.
然而 赛车界的严酷考验
'Nevertheless, the crucible of motorsport
再一次给我们答案
'had once more given us the answer.
最终 世上最厉害的出租车是
'As it turns out, the greatest taxi in the world...
印度大使
'is the Hindustan Ambassador'.
干得好 伙计 棒极了
Well done, mate. Excellent.
很赞 合理论证
Excellent. Good science.
但容我问一句 Hammond 有个重要问题
But may I ask, Hammond, an important question?
你们做那段视频 死了多少人
How many people were killed in the making of that film?
-事实上 只有三人
-三人 看到没 比我预想的要多
Actually, only three. Three. See, that's more than I was hoping for.
但为了科学 总是要做点牺牲的
But with science, there often has to be sacrifice.
但在将这些车 经受赛车界严酷考验后
But you've decided, have you not, after subjecting those cars
你已经决定了 不是吗
to the white heat of the crucible of motorsport,
世上最好的出租车是
that the best taxi in the world
-从莫里斯牛津车发展而来 -就在我们的面前
-started out in life as a Morris Oxford. -Yeah, and there it is.
这就解释了为什么造伦敦黑色出租车的公司
That would explain why the company that makes the London black cab
-会破产  -你可以这么说 但他们回来了
-has gone bust. -You say that, but they're back.
他们得到救助 即将重新生产产品
They've been rescued. They're going to start production again very soon.
最终还是毫无意义
Pointlessly, as it turns out.
是的 没错
Yes, absolutely.
好 到了全新明星廉价车环节
So, let's put a star in our brand-new reasonably-priced car.
你们或许已经意识到 今年晚些时候
Now, you may be aware that later on this year,
我们将享受电影 急速风流的盛宴
we're going to be treated to a film called Rush.
讲述1976年 为夺得
It's about the epic battle in 1976
F1年度冠军的巅峰之战
for the Formula One world championship
James Hunt与Niki Lauda两人争锋相对
between James Hunt and Niki Lauda,
而我们今日的嘉宾就是电影导演
and my guest tonight is the man who directed it.
诸位 让我们欢迎Ron Howard
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome Ron Howard!
Ron Howard本人在此
Ron Howard is here.
你好吗 真人哦
How are you? He's here!
极速风流的导演 请坐
The man who made Rush. Have a seat.
好 Ron 那么多年来
Now, Ron, over the years,
你的电影被提名29座金像奖
your films have been nominated for 29 Oscars
而你本人也赢得两座
and I think you've won two yourself.
现在你做了一部时代电影
And now you've made a historical film
有关一项体育 世界上大部分人都没看过
about a sport that most of the world doesn't really watch.
你是怎么想到 “好啊我们来做Hunt和Lauda”的呢
So why did you think, "Yeah, Hunt and Lauda"?
因为故事很棒 具有人文关怀
Great story. Great human interest story,
而我对F1的了解 足够我意识到这是个很酷的竞技体育
and I knew just enough about Formula One to just know how cool it was.
而这些角色的组合
And I felt like the combination of those characters,
人物之间的戏剧张力
the kind of human drama,
特别是70年代的F1
the world of Formula One, particularly in the '70s,
绝对能给观众带来新鲜感受
was a chance to offer something fresh to audiences.
反正这电影 我本人是要看的
It was a movie I wanted to see.
我其实对此有点紧张 因为我觉得
I was nervous about it because I thought
哦 不 他们会把电影搞得太学究
oh, no, they'll make it too nerdy
然后大家都会说 F1很无趣
and everyone will say Formula One's boring,
或者他们会为了迎合好莱坞“速度感”
or they'll do a Hollywood number of "I love speed!"
从而将场景设置在纳斯卡里
and it will all be set in NASCAR
便于美国人理解
to make it easy for the Americans to understand.
但然而 事实并非如此
And yet, it's neither of those things.
这真的是能让人回到70年代的电影
It is genuinely a film that takes you back to the '70s,
那时赛车是如此具有危险性
when motor racing was bloody dangerous.
紧张的不光是你
You weren't the only one who was nervous.
你肯定会想让粉丝们感受到 我们有好好珍视这项体育
You certainly want the fans to feel the sport's respected,
但同时又要让各个层面的受众
but you also need to make a movie that works on a lot of levels
都能享受其中
for a lot of people.
我曾在拍阿波罗13号时这么干过
I had that opportunity with Apollo 13,
那也是我最享受拍摄的电影经历之一
and it's one of the films I enjoyed making most.
我也能说 拍极速风流也很享受
And I've got to tell you, Rush was right up there.
我玩得很开心
I had a blast.
我们这里有个片段 可以给大家看看
We've got a clip for those of you who want to see what it looks like.
现在就给你们看看 那电影可真了不起
We'll show it for you now, because it is quite something.
所有赛车手都会对自己撒谎说
There's a lie that all drivers tell themselves.
死亡只会轮到别人 轮不到自己
"Death is something that happens to other people."
谁会干这种工作呢 每年 我们其中的两人就会死去
What kind of person does a job like this? Each year, two of us die.
每次坐入车舱 我都接受这一事实
I accept every time I get in my car
有百分之二十的几率 我会死去
that there's a 20% chance I could die.
驾驶时速170英里吗 这玩意简直像炸弹般要命
Being driven round at 170 mph? This thing's a bomb on wheels.
-我比你们所有人都要快  -那我们比赛呀
-I'm quicker than all of you. -Then let's race.
我是世界冠军 并且将再次蝉联
I'm a world champion on the verge to become world champion again.
我可以打败他的 相信我
I could beat this guy. Trust me.
你离死亡越近 你会越发感觉到自己活着的实感
The closer you are to death, the more alive you feel.
这绝对能让他们吓得尿裤子
This lot are going to wet themselves.
在电影中 你表现Niki Lauda 种种缺点
In the film, you show Niki Lauda, warts and all.
我从来没想到过他会是那样 这个强迫症 很直接的人
I had no idea he was like that, this OCD, very straight guy.
他最后看到成品什么反应
How did he react when he saw the finished product?
他看了很感动
When he saw it, he was moved by it,
我觉得那是因为 对于那起事故
and I think it was because he never really had a perspective
他从未以其他角度来看
on that period around the accident.
首先 他不太记得了
First of all, he couldn't remember much of it.
其次 他只记得愤怒 众人当时如何
Secondly, what he does remember was all about the anger that people were
写他 以为他要死了
writing him off, thought he had died.
他都知道 以及目光短浅急于回来比赛
He could hear that. And also the myopic drive to get back in the car.
他就这么一根筋 基本上屏蔽掉其他所有事情
He was so single-minded that he blanked everything else out
而当他看这电影时 开始意识到
and when he saw this he began to realise what other
自己周围的人 特别是当时的夫人Marlene
people around him, Marlene, his wife then, in particular,
他们又经历了哪些 以更人文关怀的角度
what they were going through, and a more human side of it.
我觉得这点对他来说 很受情绪催动
and I think it was emotional for him to deal with.
同时你也将James Hunt
Then of course you've got James Hunt
刻画为与其竞争的角色
as the complete counterbalance to that.
我们在办公室墙上挂着James Hunt的照片
We've got a picture of James Hunt which we keep on our office wall.
基本上就可以完全总结他这个人 他的赛车
This just sums him up. His pop-riveted car.
他在想 等下我抽完了这根烟
He's thinking, "When I've finished this cigarette
喝完这罐酒 你 亲爱的 就是下一个
"and this can of beer, you, my dear, are next."
不过今天你就看不到这些了 真是悲剧
You just don't see this today. It is one of the tragedies.
你没法见到摆这姿势的尼克·罗斯伯格
You can't see Nico Rosberg posing.
如今他们只会这样 我想感谢我的手表制造商
"I would like to thank my watch manufacturer
我的帽子厂商 以及制油的人们
"and my hat manufacturer and the people who made my oil."
这就是我很喜欢当时的原因
That's what I really like about it.
这两个家伙 不归属于任何人
There are two guys, who bowed to no-one.
当时没有尤达大师指引他们去往崇高目标
There was no Yoda guiding them to their higher purpose.
他们都是以个人来定义自己
These were guys who defined themselves on their own terms,
虽然两人完全不同 而他们也背负着各自决定所带来的伤疤
very different terms, and they would bear the scars
但他们也能举起奖杯赢得胜利
of those decisions, but they also could certainly claim the triumphs.
我确定在场的所有人 我们转移话题聊开了去
I'm sure everybody in the room here... We move off Rush.
我确定在场的所有人看着你 在想
I'm sure everybody in the room here is looking at you thinking,
超过40岁的人们会想 你可真脸熟
everyone over 40 that is, thinking that is a familiar face,
因为有些人没意识到 你曾出演过情景喜剧 欢乐时光
because a lot of people don't realise that you were in Happy Days.
你是Richie Cunningham
You are Richie Cunningham.
没错
I was him.
我觉得这就是人们意难平的地方
It's one of those things I think people find hard to equate.
你是位优秀电影导演 但之前是喜剧演员
Here's this amazing film director, but you were,
所以你改换了方向 让我念念
so you really did obviously switch into directing and I was just
你之前导过的有名电影
making a list of the better-known ones that you've directed and...
真是了不起
This is extraordinary.
有 美人鱼 魔茧 阿波罗13号 达芬奇密码 美丽心灵
It's Splash, Cocoon, Apollo 13, Da Vinci Code, Beautiful Mind,
对话尼克松 天使与魔鬼
Frost/Nixon, Angels & Demons,
回火 温馨家族 那部很好笑呃 赎金
Backdraft, Parenthood - that's very funny - Ransom.
我想 等等 他演了欢乐时光 导了那么多电影
I'm just thinking, "Hang on a minute, he did Happy Days and all
而我做个汽车节目就累得不行 你时间哪里来的
"that. I do a car show and I'm flat-out." How do you find the time?
因为我非常享受自己的工作 都不需要其他兴趣爱好
The simple answer is I enjoy what I'm doing, so I don't need a hobby.
我就爱干这行
I love this.
出演欢乐时光后 你差不多一直在
Having been on a show like Happy Days, you sort of are doing
重复相同的人物
the same character over and over
而当我意识到自己有机会成为导演后
and when I realised I had a chance to be a director I thought,
我想要尽可能做多元化的事情
"I want to do as many diverse things as I possibly can."
所以我租了个16毫米摄像机
So I was renting 16mm cameras,
拍了自己第一部独立电影
making my own little independent movies.
然后自己的第一部电影 也是关于车的
Eventually doing my first movie, which was a car movie,
疯狂恋爱跑天下 没错 车祸喜剧
Grand Theft Auto. Of course. Car crash comedy.
那是我在拍欢乐时光的间隙制作的
I did that during one of the hiatuses from Happy Days.
-请允许我将话题转到你的个人生活上 你有四个孩子吗  -没错
Moving onto personal life if I may, four children? Yes.
-他们的中间名很让我感兴趣  -是啊 我猜也是
Their middle names interest me. Oh, yeah, I guess they might.
你有一个孩子的中间名叫 Dellas
You've got one called, middle name of Dallas. Yes.
-我猜名字来源于  -城市Dellas  -在那儿她
-Which I believe was named... -After the city.  -Where...?
她是在那里被怀上的
She was conceived. Yes.
然后你有一对双胞胎 他们的中间名是Carlyle
Then you've got twins, both of whom have the middle name Carlyle.
没错 在纽约有加旅馆叫 The Carlyle
Yes. In New York there is a lovely hotel called The Carlyle...
好吧 然后
OK. And...
然后我们往前推想时间 然后觉得
And we sorted that one out, kind of backtracked, and thought,
-那个当中间名也不错啊 要保持这一传统  -好
-"That's a very beautiful middle name, let's keep the tradition." -OK.
-小儿子叫Cross -Cross 全名是Reed Cross Howard
-The youngest son is called Cross. -Cross. Reed Cross Howard.
我们后来发现又怀上孩子了 很好
We sort of found out we were pregnant again. Great.
好 那让我们回想下
"All right, well let's sort through it.
不知道能不能想起来
"I wonder if we can figure it out.
沃尔沃可没法当中间名
（原来在车里 =_____=）
"Volvo is not much of a middle name."
是啊 沃尔沃可不行
And... Yeah, Volvo doesn't work.
但附近有条路叫Lower Cross Road
But there is a road near us called Lower Cross Road.
就是那辆沃尔沃所停之处
Which is where the Volvo was.
-我们婚姻很幸福  -可以想见 理查德也这么做了
We have a good marriage. Evidently. Richard Hammond does the same.
我那天和他的孩子聊天
I was talking to his kids the other day.
他们叫 公交车站 和 垃圾桶旁
They're called Bus Stop and By The Bins.
好 你是第一位正式开我们全新
Now, you are the first person to properly drive our brand-new
廉价车的嘉宾
reasonably-priced car.
-是呀  -你感觉如何
-Yes.  -What did you think of it?
首先我要说 右侧驾驶
First of all I will say the right-hand drive
而变速杆在左边 真让我不习惯
and the gearshift on the left was a concern to me.
是正确的方式
The correct way round.
绝对 让我困惑难安
It was... It definitely threw me.
在你放之前 我也向大家恳求
And I also implore, before you get into all this, I implore anyone who
如果你们对电影感兴趣的话 在电影里开车的不是我
has any interest in seeing my movie Rush, I didn't drive in the movie.
是真正的赛车手
Real drivers drove in the movie.
好 这就是你脱身的借口
Right, there's your excuses out of the way.
谁想看看Ron的单圈
Now who'd like to see Ron's lap?
想
Yes
-让我们来看看 -哦老天
-Let's have a look. -Oh, Lord.
看一看
Let's have a look.
看看这起步咆哮的车子
Look at that mighty machine leaping off the line.
你可得坚持住 Ron
You've got to stick it, Ron.
你真的得坚持住
You've got to really stick it.
Niki对我教导了一番
Niki was giving me a little coaching the other day.
这是Niki Laud解释
That's Niki Lauda's explanation.
你可得坚持住 你真的得坚持住
"You've got to stick it. You've got to really stick it."
老天爷 这算是坚持住了吗
Holy smokes. Is that sticking it?
我不知道 只走了赛道的一边
I don't know! Not using all the track.
很平滑
Smooth.
好 我可不知道
Right. I don't know.
车在那儿一段抓地很好
That car is gripping quite well there.
这一段我总是开得不顺
This is the one that always destroys me.
恐怖的锤头弯
The fearsome Hammerhead.
我真的搞砸了 是吧
I look like I'm being destroyed, don't I?
这看上去不错 真的很不错 非常紧凑
This is looking good. That's very good. Very tidy.
听听引擎声呀
Listen to that engine(!)
-哇 这车可真猛  -注意力集中
Wow, what a machine this is(!) Concentrate here a little bit.
看到没 我可是认真对待
See, I'm taking it seriously.
确实 那是注意力集中的表情
You were. That is a man who is concentrating.
经过连续弯时轮胎备受折磨 很漂亮
Tyres tortured as he goes through the follow-through. Nicely done.
切弯很好 让我们看看倒数第二弯
Nicely cut. Let's have a look at the second-to-last corner.
这里总会有点 哇 爽气
This is the bit normally catch... Oh! Bang on.
而到甘邦弯 看看这抓地 干得真不错
And then on into Gambon and look at that grip. That's bloody good.
然后我们冲过终点
There we are across the line.
哇
Wow.
-谢谢 -那么 Ron 板上成绩不多
-Thank you. -So, Ron, not many times on the board.
-你觉得自己排名如何  -老天
-Where do you think you've come? -Lord.
比我想象中的要好一点
It wasn't quite as ugly as I imagined it would be.
导演的眼光让我觉得自己很糟糕
My director's eye on the outside had it looking pretty bad.
看上去很顺畅 没法说有多快 但很顺
It looked smooth. Not sure about fast, but it looked smooth.
你觉得在哪里
Where do we think?
我只希望自己别垫底
I'd like to think I'm not flat on the bottom.
那一位是Genesis的Mike Rutherford
That would be Mike Rutherford out of Genesis.
我怀疑自己就在最后
I suspect I'm right down there.
-我是这么想的  -Ron Howard 你的成绩是 1分
That's where I think. Ron Howard, you did it in 1...
好 是个好开头
Right. So that's good. OK.
-40 -哦 所以不是垫底 还不错
-..40.  -Oh, OK, not the very bottom. So that's good. OK.
但接下来一位数并不是太好
The next bit's not so good.
9秒9
..9.9.
所以 你不是最后一名
OK. You're not the bottom.
那也意味着 我们终于找到了
So what this means is we've finally found something
你不擅长的事物了
you can't do.
擅长导演 在欢乐时光里 表现极佳
Good at directing, brilliant in Happy Days,
很有魅力的人 但驾驶水平糟糕
a charming human being, but utterly crap at driving.
-说得有道理 -诸位 Ron Howard 谢谢你
Fair enough. Ladies and gentlemen, Ron Howard. Thank you.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
你们有可能在几个月之前见证了
Now you may have seen that a few
months ago
著名的BBC电视演播中心的关闭仪式
the famous BBC TV Centre
closed down.
那一刻 电波中弥漫着
When it did, the airwaves were
swamped with emotional
电视界大佬们的颂词
tributes from the giants
of television.
例如 罗尼·柯贝特 大卫·爱登堡 迈克尔·帕金森。
Ronnie Corbett, David
Attenborough, Michael Parkinson.
但是Top Gear却没能参与其中 而现在
But nothing from Top Gear.
Until now.
这就是我们所谈论的那栋大楼
This is the building in question.
53年以来 它一直是世界上某些标志性
For 53 years, it was the engine
room for some of the most iconic
电视节目的源泉
television in the world.
但是如今 这里所剩无几
But now, today,
this is all that's left.
但这也是个好消息
And that is great news
因为我们发现一旦把
because what we've realised is that
once you take away all
人员和茶几等全部清空，然后锁上门
the people and the tea trolley
and you've locked all the doors
这栋被抛弃的大楼就变成了一个极佳的赛场
this abandoned building makes
an excellent venue for a race.
这些弯曲的走廊
You have these curving corridors
that could be long, fast
好比顶级F1赛道上的快速弯
sweepers on a top F1 track.
还有这些漂亮的办公室 充斥着各种有趣障碍物
You have these beautiful offices
full of interesting obstacles
以及技巧性弯道。
and technical turns.
同时 你可以好好在室外透透气
And you have all this outdoor area
where you can literally
（暗指进行腾空的特技表演）
get some air.
总体来说 这是一个公认的独特而刺激的赛场
All in all, a unique and exciting
racing circuit I think you'll agree.
至于参赛选手嘛
And so to the racers.
很不幸 因为杰瑞米前阵子用Peel P50证明过
isn't very suitable for cars,
这栋大楼不适合汽车通行
Now, unfortunately this building
as indeed Jeremy proved a
while back with the Peel P50.
所以今天我们会让他们进行对决 他们仨
So today we'll be racing these two.
Of which there are three.
我们有道吉·拉姆金骑士
We have Dougie Lampkin MBE,
获得过16个世界冠军头衔的计时赛摩托车手
a trials rider with 16 World
Titles to his name.
他的对手是蒂姆·歇尔夫和保罗·约瑟夫，
And he's up against Tim Shieff
and Paul Joseph,
两个世界上最牛的跑酷选手
two of the finest Free
Runners on the planet.
他们俩之间虽然没有发动机
They may not have an
engine between them
但显然他们可以沿着走廊飞奔
but apparently they can
run along corridors and scamper over
还能像兴奋的松鼠一样 在阳台和消防通道来回蹦跶
balconies and fire escapes
like a couple of randy squirrels.
参赛选手介绍结束
So with the introductions over,
let's look at the route
让我们来看看比赛路线
of the race itself.
这是电视演播中心的鸟瞰图
Here we have a birds' eye
view of Television Centre.
实际上只是个模型
It's actually only a model.
你会看到它形似一个问号
And you will see it's shaped
a little bit like a question mark.
我提议从这个地方开始比赛
So what I'm proposing is
we start here, which is
差不多是我们现在站的地方
roughly where we're standing now,
从这个问号的底部进入建筑物
enter the building at the base of
the question mark
然后在建筑里面一路赛到这里结束
and then race all the way
through it to finish here
就在那个上面
which is up there.
随着激动的观赛人群开始聚集
'As an excited crowd gathered,
I positioned
我自己站到了终点线的位置
'myself on the finish line.'
各就各位 3,2,1
Are you ready? In three, two,
one.
HORN
有趣的是 道吉·拉姆金选择穿门而过。
This is interesting. Dougie Lampkin
has chosen to go through the door.
但两个小青年选择从外部攀爬而上
'But the youths are making their way
up the outside of the building
这主意不错
which actually isn't such a bad
idea'
因为你一旦进入建筑内就被束缚了
because once you're inside here,
you will be completely baffled.
如果他们呆在建筑的外面
If they stay on the outside they
will have some idea
他们就会知道到底在朝哪行进
of where they're going.'
好样的
Good thinking.
不错 这个可以让我通过大楼的闭路摄像头
Right, this should allow me to get
a direct feed
来直接观察比赛动向
from any of the
CCTV cameras around the building.
这是那两个不安分的小伙子
And there are the jumpy boys.
他俩现在是突发新闻
They are literally breaking news.
当两个小青年穿过新闻演播室的时候
As the youths made their way
through the newsroom,
道吉·拉姆金正在寻找上楼的路线
'Dougie was looking for a way
upstairs.'
他在这里
There is Dougie Lampkin.
在新闻之夜演播间 两个年轻人走了死胡同
In the Newsnight office, the youths
had found their path blocked
他们不得不再次下楼。
and were having to
make their way down again.'
又发现自己其实被锁在了BBC酒吧
Having found himself literally in a
lock-in in the BBC bar
道吉同样也得再找一条下楼的路
Dougie too needed to find a way
back down.'
天知道他会在“问号”的根部
So he is, God knows,
somewhere over in the main
和弯头连接的什么地方冒出来
leg of the question mark just
approaching the curvy bit.
我也不清楚到底哪边领先 但是比赛相当刺激
I've no idea who's in the lead,
but it's very exciting.
哥们 那个门是锁着的
That, chaps, is a locked door.'
卫生部表示
The Health and Safety department
will have something to
有话要说
say about that.
回到演播室 戴立克
Into the studio and the Daleks still
waiting
还在楼梯底下呆着
at the bottom of the stairs
there.
令人惊讶的是即使两个年轻人在六楼的
Amazingly even though the youths
were now at the management
管理层办公室里面
offices on the sixth floor
做起决定也不磨叽
they were having no trouble
making decisions.'
与此同时 在彻底败给了BBC的迷宫走廊后
Meanwhile Dougie, now completely
frustrated by the maze
道吉决定采取一套更加直接的解决方案。
of BBC corridors, had
decided on a more direct approach.'
噢
Oh.
我想道吉·拉姆金正赶往楼顶
And Dougie Lampkin is going onto
the roof I believe.
我能听到摩托车的声音
I can hear a bike.
女士们先生们 获胜者是道吉·拉姆金
It's Dougie Lampkin,
ladies and gentlemen!
一场对BBC电视演播中心的
What a fantastic two-wheeled
tribute
惊艳摩托礼赞
（电视中心邮编是：W12 8QT）
to BBC Television Centre
W12 8QT.
先生 恭喜你。
Congratulations, sir.
那两个跑酷的哥们呢
Where are the Free Runners?
他们来了
And here they come.
蒂姆·歇尔夫 保罗·约瑟夫 很接近
Tim Shieff, Paul Joseph, close,
但还是略有差距
not quite close enough,
无论如何还是好样的
but well done anyway.
完美 给力的比赛 获胜者道吉·拉姆金感觉如何
Well done, great race. Your victor,
Dougie Lampkin. How was it?
我累坏了 那玩意就像一迷宫。
I'm knackered.
That thing's a labyrinth.
你们应该知道那个高高的东西是电梯吧
You know there's a lift?
In that tall bit there.
你们可以坐它直达屋顶
You just go straight up to the top.
太不可思议了 那俩哥们的动作我一个都不会
That was incredible. I couldn't do
a single thing that those guys did.
我曾想去骑摩托车 但我带不上头盔
I was going to do the bike.
I couldn't put the helmet on.
那一个腾空跳跃真是碉堡了
The jumps were amazing.
我只想说在录制这段影片的时候
I just want to say that
when I made that film
电视演播中心已经关闭了 但就在那时
Television Centre had closed, but
since then, owing to the unique way
由于BBC奇葩的运营方式 中心被再次启用
the BBC is run,
they've decided to open it again.
LAUGHTER
-额 所以你为一个不会关闭的建筑物拍了一段纪念影片
-是滴
Right, so you've made a tribute film
to a building that isn't shut? Yes.
-这就像为霍莉·威洛比写讣告
-是的。
（霍莉·威洛 著名模特）
Isn't that like making an obituary
for Holly Willoughby? Yes.
但是想象一下当你发现她依旧活着的时候
But imagine how pleased you'd be
你会有多高兴
when you found out
she was still alive.
-就是这个道理
-同志们 我能打断一下吗
That's a point. Chaps,
may I interrupt?
我非常喜欢你的出租车大击爆
Because I much enjoyed your
smashing-up-the-taxi film
还有你的在摩托车手和
and your race
between the motorcyclist
两个路人大对决 但恐怕我们现在要严肃一点
and the two pedestrians, but I'm
afraid we have to get serious now.
因为我们收到了一封来信 哦不！信是来自
Because we've had a letter.
Oh, no! It's from...
一个说话拐弯抹角心胸狭窄的呆子
Well, it's from a mealy-mouthed,
small-minded idiot.
他说到:"亲爱的杰瑞米·克拉克森 由于英国太过拥挤
And it says, "Dear Jeremy Clarkson,
because Britain is so crowded
交通拥堵严重 拥有一辆法拉利其实毫无意义
"and there's so much traffic,
there's no point owning a Ferrari
同理可得 在节目里试一辆法拉利也毫无意义"
"and therefore no point road
testing them on your programme."
呵呵 我不同意 二呆小气先生的观点
Well, now I disagree,
Mr Small-minded Idiot.
因为在英国 有很多地方
Because there are plenty of places
in Britain
其实一点也不拥挤。
that aren't crowded at all.
这里是赫特福德郡。
This is Hertfordshire.
离伦敦仅40英里 是驾驶者的天堂。
It's just 40 miles from London
and it's motoring nirvana.
万事俱备
Mmm! We have everything we need.
广阔的景色 迂回的道路 没有交通堵塞
Huge scenery, swooping road,
no traffic.
对那些习惯在圣餐酒上标上辛烷值的人来说
The Holy Trinity for anyone whose
communion wine comes with
这简直是三位一体的感觉
an octane rating.
在英国不能享受一辆法拉利 怎么可能
Can't enjoy a Ferrari in Britain?
Oh, yes, you can.
但是你能消受我开的这台么
But can you enjoy THIS one?
他的名字叫F12。
It's called the F12.
她价值240,000镑 因为有台730马力V12发动机
It costs £240,000 and thanks to
a 730 horsepower V12 it's
她是目前法拉利所生产的马力最大的街车
the most powerful road-going
Ferrari ever made.
其实它阿隆索的F1赛车一样猛
It's almost as powerful, in fact, as
Fernando Alonso's Formula 1 racer.
当然这时 那些吃饱了撑着的人会说
Of course, at this point, people
with mouths of meal would say,
"这么些马力在限速面前到底有何意义"
"What's the point of all that
when we've got speed limits?"
你不必每时每刻都用尽所有的马力
You don't have to use
all of it all the time.
在小镇里面 你可放松坐着 打开收音机
In a town, you can sit back,
turn on the radio,
把悬架设置为颠簸路面模式
put the suspension in bumpy road
mode to make everything nice
让一切变得安逸而舒适 把变速箱和空调
and comfy, set the gearbox in
automatic,
都设置为自动
the air conditioning just so,
然后你就可以很愉悦的以每小时20英里兜风
and then you can drive along quite
happily at 20 miles an hour.
轻松 这车还不会显得特别大
Easy. 'It's not even
especially big.'
我当然不是说这车很袖珍
I'm not saying this is tiny,
但不是宽大的太离谱 你不用每次变道都这么狰狞
but it's not preposterous. You don't
go through every gap like that.
所以这车在莱奇沃斯就和别的车一样好开
So this car works in Letchworth
just like any other car.
但驶出城区以后 一切就变得十分与众不同
But when the built-up area ends,
it's not like any other car at all.
喔 真快
Wow. Wow, this is fast.
法拉利官方称 0至到60英里加速需3.1秒
Ferrari say it will
go from 0 to 60 in 3.1 seconds.
极速可达每小时211英里
And that flat-out, it will be
doing 211 miles an hour.
而且不仅强有力的发动机使这辆车如此狂暴
And it's not just the massive engine
which makes it all so savage.
与老款的599不同 这辆车配备了双离合器变速箱
Unlike the old 599, this has
a double clutch gearbox,
所以换挡十分直接迅速
so gear changes are immediate.
你只要飚起来 直到浪声血洗你的耳朵
You build up the speed
until the noise gets too much
然后升档
and your ears are bleeding
and then you change up
没有换挡间隙 衔接十分流畅 这是怎么做到的
and there's no gap. How do
you do that?
他们还给这车配备了更复杂的牵引力控制系统
They've also fitted a more
sophisticated traction
可以使你享受的同时不发生车祸
control system which lets you have
fun without allowing you to crash.
但最惊艳的是这辆车如何腾云驾雾
But the most impressive thing is how
this car manages the air.
这些薄片 在刹车片温度升高的时候会打开
These flaps down here,
when the brakes are hot, they open,
用气流冷却刹车
to allow cooling air to
pass on to the discs.
但其他的时候 他们会关闭 来保证更好的空气动力学效应
But the rest of the time, they're
shut for better aerodynamics.
再来看看引擎盖两侧的风道
And then you have these channels
on either side of the bonnet.
空气被沿着这些通道汇集起来
The air is funnelled along them
进入这里然后从这里流出
into here and out of here
so it provides a boundary
让气流更为爽滑地
layer of smooth air passing down the
flanks of the car
流经车身侧面
making it more slippery.
而且还提供了非常实在的下压力
There's real downforce as well.
在车速为125英里每小时的时候
At 125 miles an hour,
the weight of the air
空气压到车身上的重量可以达到19英石。
pressing down on the car
is 19 stone.
仿佛让约翰·普莱斯科坐在车顶上
That's like having half
of John Prescott on the roof forcing
迫使轮胎紧贴沥青路面 来获取更好的抓地力
the tyres into the Tarmac,
giving better grip.
他们用尽一切所学的知识
They have done everything
in the book to exploit
来榨取出强大的火力。
the colossal firepower.
而成果让人如痴如醉
And the results are mesmerising.
在过去 法拉利让人感觉笨重
In the past, big Ferraris felt big.
Testarossa 612 都巨大无比 他们就像大胖子的座驾
The Testarossa, the 612, they were
immense. They were fat-boy cars.
这一辆却不是 它很轻 很灵活 很犀利。
This isn't. This is light
and nimble and sharp.
这车棒极了
It's... It is spectacular.
我必须承认 虽然这辆车很给力
I must confess though that
while the car is fine,
但我却很挣扎 因为在这车里面我感觉有些躁动
I am struggling, because
it is a bit frantic in here.
我刚刚飞了车
I just went airborne then.
你们了解早期的飞行员在两马赫的速度下
You read about those early test
pilots in Mach Two
测试喷气式战斗机的极限状态的那种感觉
jet fighters going to the very
limits of what was possible.
就跟我坐在这里的感受一样 感觉自己快疯了
That's what it feels like in this -
like you're sort of out of control.
而且这辆车的转向不可思议的灵敏
And it has incredibly fast steering,
so the slightest movement
方向盘上任何细小的动作都会使车辆偏转
of the wheel causes an immediate
dart one way or the other.
再就是油门的问题
And then there's the throttle.
一脚油门下去 你本想说:"哦 耶"
You put your foot down
and you think, "Whoa, yes,"
然后你立马反应:"诶 卧槽 吓尿了"
and then immediately you think,
"No, actually. Too scary."
当你的生活如此富有激情的时候
And when life is as hectic as this,
what you really
你想要的是让操控回归传统
want are for all the controls
to be conventional.
但事实并非如此
And they're not.
所有控制灯光 雨刷 包括转向灯
All the knobs and buttons
for the lights and the wipers
的拨杆和按钮 都在旋转的方向盘上
and the indicators are all
on the steering wheel
所以他们从来不会停留在原来的位置
which moves about, so they're never
where you left them.
你甚至不能在开这车的时候打喷嚏
You can't even sneeze
when you're driving this car
因为如果你打了 喷嚏就会带你亲近路边水沟
because if you did... Well, they'd
have to hose you off the road.
为了向你们解释我到底是神马意思
To try and explain
what I'm on about,
我来到了这片网球场
I've come to this tennis court.
现在好比在赫特福德郡的道路上
This is what it's like to drive
an ordinary car
驾驶一辆普通汽车
on the roads of Hertfordshire.
来吧 高尔夫GTi
There you go, Golf GTI...
宝马 M3 法拉利 458 这很简单
BMW M3, Ferrari 458. This is easy
而且易于掌控
and manageable
我可以一整天都干这个
and I could do it all day.
现在让我来展示一下驾驶F12
Now let me show you what
it's like to drive
是个神马感受
a Ferrari F12.
啊哦 擦 打脸了
Ugh! Ugh! Oh, in the face!
Stig说 这是世界上唯一一辆能让LFA
The Stig says, this is the only
car in the world that can hold
望其项背的车。
a candle to the Lexus LFA.
他还说到这是他开过的法拉利里
He also says it's the first Ferrari
he's ever driven that he
第一辆激起他购买欲望的车
would actually buy -
前提是他有金钱的概念 但显然他没有
if he had any concept of money,
which of course he doesn't.
在我看来 虽然这车已经堪称完美
Me, though... It is brilliant,
但我认为 如果转向稍微迟钝一点 动力稍弱一点
but I think it would be better still
if it had slower steering...
会更好 虽然这话我自己都觉得难以启齿
and it's hard for me to say this,
but a bit less power.
是的 你可以在英国享受这辆车带来的快感
Yes, you can really enjoy it
in Britain,
但是你无法消受这辆车的全部潜能
but you can't really enjoy
all of it.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
太棒了 我还是继续选择LFA
It is frantic.
I'd still have an LFA.
尽管F12长长的选装清单
The LFA is 100 grand more
让这车的价格飙升至35万英镑
although the options on this,
LFA还是要贵10万多
they do take it up to 350 as well.
等一下  你说啥
Hang on, hang on, hang on. What?
杰瑞米·克拉克森 我刚才是不是听到你说
Did I just hear you,
Jeremy Clarkson,
-"马力稍微弱一点"
-是的 你没听错
say that you'd like "a bit less
power"? Yes, you did.
这是不是有点像戈登·拉姆齐说
Isn't that a bit like Gordon Ramsay
saying, "Yes, I like this dish,
"我喜欢这道菜 但我希望菜的味道淡一点就更好了"
"but I wish it had a bit less
flavour."
或者詹姆斯·梅说到
Or James May saying,
"Yes, I like this, but can it be
"是的 我喜欢这个 但是棕色能少些吗"
"a bit less brown?"
是的 的确如此 但这是一个爆炸性新闻意味着 节目可以结束了
No, it is like that, but it is a
bombshell, which means we can end.
感谢大家的收看 我们下周再见 保重
Thank you very much for watching.
See you all next week. Take care.
大家晚安
Good night.